<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mood | Themis_Sword's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/categories/mood/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-15T19:13:06+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Themis_Sword]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[licong0419@outlook.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/12012014/dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T16:37:15+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/12012014/dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/adventure.jpg"></p>

<p>今天，2014年最後一個月的第一天，是該收拾下情緒了。</p>

<p>2014年，普通的不能再普通的一年，卻夾雜了太多的變化，這些變化，甚至改變了未來的方向。<!--more--></p>

<p>去年的辭職空檔期甚至延續到了今年的前五個月，超過整整七個月的空檔期，要算焦灼，還是焦慮，此刻的自己都回憶不起來那時，到底是什麼樣的心境。</p>

<p>還好，工作只是糊口的家什，事業才是值得追求和爭取的。</p>

<p>於是，工作，辭職，又工作。</p>

<p>直到現在，依然還算是沒有脫離“工作”的羈絆吧。</p>

<p>苦盡甘來？或許之前也不算苦，即使大半年像個游魂。</p>

<p>結識了True Friends，也遇到了她。</p>

<p>更安心了，就像久枯之地突然流過潺潺溪水；就靜靜的，靜靜的，直到心裏。如果硬要說有什麼不安，可能，是擔心自己不夠出色，不夠優秀，讓她委屈。</p>

<p>也收到了大學的offer，即將在新年啟程，去另一個國家，開始求學之旅，開始另一種人生。</p>

<p>自己很幸運，很幸運，不然，不會同時擁有，擁有一個愛人，擁有一份美好的未來。</p>

<p>此刻，耳機裏正好傳來最喜歡的那首“Forever in Love”。</p>

<p>感恩節剛過，如果說把“感恩”說出來，一遍兩遍三遍，未免太矯情。如此，心裏知道，便好。不求其他的，只求無愧、無悔。</p>

<p>還好，掙扎了這麼多年，還沒放棄。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pieces]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/08302014/pieces/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-30T22:15:03+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/08302014/pieces</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/owlcoffee.jpg"></p>

<p>A friend said I am a traditional person intrinsically somehow with an attempt to break the invisible shackles, the boundary of the traditional and the nontraditional. I know it&rsquo;s true for I am raised and influenced since my juvenile in such family and society.<!--more--></p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s define the word &ldquo;traditional&rdquo; with the meaning of life styles with or close to Eastern world, and the word &ldquo;nontraditional&rdquo; with the opposite one.</p>

<p>With thousands years' culture of the doctrine of the mean in Eastern world, it would be so easy about choosing just like an objective question, following the tide and keeping away from too leftward or too rightward. It is also believed safe and reliable. If I am always as pure as a plain paper about my mind, there would be never so troublesome.</p>

<p>If comparing the modes of thinking as a curve of Normal Distribution, the curve in the Eastern world is supposed to be steep and thin while the curve in the Western world is supposed to be flat and fat, that is the difference. Persons' innate thoughts and exterior activities in the two environments are pulled or pushed from the two types of curve.</p>

<p>No readings, no worries. Especially when reading so many books about different life styles, thoughts, viewpoints and experiences of this flat world, notions' sparking and colliding in the consciousness. While endeavoring to experience colorful diversities of life, the farther you deviate, the stronger viscous forces pull you back to the curve. (Based on the theory of evolution, it would take tens or hundreds of generations to have a thorough change, of that curve, for the whole society.) And I also believe, it&rsquo;s true.</p>

<p>Retrospecting myself, what I would like to do is exploring this magnificent earth by reading thousands of books and traveling thousands of miles. Only after that, I could have a proper state of mind to choose and settle down. I would like to live a fresh and unique myself without considering what the general trends' choices. Obviously that&rsquo;s the reason  I am who I am. I would try to make some tiny changes within an invisible scope, the so-called margin of safety. As for others, I would be not so sure. Maybe that, the flounder, is some proof of my youth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hurt]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/07102014/hurt/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-10T16:52:28+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/07102014/hurt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vt1Pwfnh5pc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I hurt myself today<br/>
To see if I still feel  <!--more-->
I focus on the pain<br/>
The only thing that&rsquo;s real<br/>
The needle tears a hole<br/>
The old familiar sting<br/>
Try to kill it all away<br/>
But I remember everything</p>

<p>What have I become<br/>
My sweetest friend<br/>
Everyone I know goes away<br/>
In the end<br/>
And you could have it all<br/>
My empire of dirt<br/>
I will let you down<br/>
I will make you hurt</p>

<p>I wear this crown of thorns<br/>
Upon my liar&rsquo;s chair<br/>
Full of broken thoughts<br/>
I cannot repair<br/>
Beneath the stains of time<br/>
The feelings disappear<br/>
You are someone else<br/>
I am still right here</p>

<p>What have I become<br/>
My sweetest friend<br/>
Everyone I know goes away<br/>
In the end<br/>
And you could have it all<br/>
My empire of dirt<br/>
I will let you down<br/>
I will make you hurt</p>

<p>If I could start again<br/>
A million miles away<br/>
I would keep myself<br/>
I would find a way</p>

<p><strong>What would remain imperishably while lines' etching on the face? A word, some memories, or just serenity with or without regret.</strong></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Job, New Way]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/06142014/new-job/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-14T10:04:25+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/06142014/new-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/bigdata.jpg"></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s been a whole month working in a new company, which is a venture company with the area of distributed storage focused.<!--more--></p>

<p>Returning back to Beijing after half a year&rsquo;s separation, living in a high-rise apartment, I soon realized, it would be a new way.</p>

<p>Everything&rsquo;s changed whereas everything seems the same.</p>

<p>NEW CHALLENGES come with the new position. Studying and reading fulfill every day and almost every minute, that joys me. I could see vigor&rsquo;s back and fresh air&rsquo;s pervading.</p>

<p>Time to transform and evolve.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Are Alive]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/05042014/you-are-alive/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-04T20:21:19+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/05042014/you-are-alive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/alive.jpg"></p>

<p>如果你的內心有不安<br/>
If you&rsquo;re carrying your restlessness in your heart,<!--more--><br/>
那麽你還活著<br/>
you are alive<br/>
如果你的眼中有對夢想的渴望<br/>
If you&rsquo;re carrying the flames of dreams in your eyes,<br/>
那麽你還活著<br/>
you are alive<br/>
像一陣風一般的自由生活<br/>
Like a gust of wind, learn to live free<br/>
學著像大海的波浪般流動<br/>
Learn to flow like the waves that make a sea<br/>
張開你的雙臂擁抱每個時刻，你都可能收獲一份問候<br/>
May every moment gift you a new sight to greet<br/>
如果你的眼中有期望<br/>
If you&rsquo;re carrying wonder in your eyes,<br/>
那麽你還活著<br/>
you are alive<br/>
如果你的內心有不安<br/>
If you&rsquo;re carrying your restlessness in your heart<br/>
那麽你還活著<br/>
you are alive</p>

<p>&mdash;From Indian Movie <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1562872/">&ldquo;Zindagi Na Milegi Dobara&rdquo;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
