<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mood | Themis_Sword's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/categories/mood/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-16T17:04:50+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Themis_Sword]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[licong0419@outlook.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stay Hungry, Stay Foolish]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04082014/stay-hungry/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-08T14:43:38+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04082014/stay-hungry</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/stayhsf.png"><br/>
<strong>&ldquo;Stay Hungry, Stay Foolish.&rdquo;</strong> Such resounding words delivered by Steve Jobs were in 2005 Stanford Commencement Address which, was actually not the topic today. The quote is just about some reflections of a movie <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0107048/"><em>Groundhog Day</em></a>.<!--more--></p>

<p><strong>&ldquo;What would you do if you were stuck in one place and every day was exactly the same, and nothing that you did mattered?&rdquo;</strong></p>

<p>Phil Connors, the hero in that movie, an arrogant and egocentric Pittsburgh TV weatherman who, during a disgusted assignment covering the annual Groundhog Day event in Punxsutawney, finds himself in a time loop, repeating the same day over and over and over again. After indulging in periods of hedonism, dismay, bitterness, despair then numerous suicide attempts, he begins to re-examine his life and tries to change &mdash; improving and enriching himself through learning new skills and helping people.</p>

<p>Some plots are interesting that when Phil tries harder and harder to cater to someone he is interested, either terrible consequences(such as slaps on his face) come or void&rsquo;s arising even he succeeds. It might be because Phil attempts to alter the original himself which he actually couldn&rsquo;t. Such alternation would not last long even though he makes it for a flash. Only when Phil accepts the circumstances calmly, patiently and ready to do some &ldquo;changes&rdquo; would he handle the &ldquo;magic&rdquo; to break such time loop and win his queen&rsquo;s heart.</p>

<p>And so is the story telling us.</p>

<p>In real life, things are so similar that few ones are satisfied with their presents living roughly the same days over and over and over again. Senses of helplessness and so far as abomination towards their own never vanish. Sorrowfully that only fewer ones would like or dare to make a change as to be sluggish, revolted and desperate dying finally.</p>

<p>Staying hungry and foolish, is only for adequate constant advances for the nature of oneself could not be changed but the substance. There would be one and the only way to get rid of such suck life rhythm is to get cultured. Never scared, even if looked like deserted weeds temporarily. Just endeavor, struggle, enrich oneself, waiting patiently for the moment handling that fabulous magic to break one&rsquo;s own &ldquo;time loop&rdquo;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fading away]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04022014/fading-away/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-02T20:21:50+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04022014/fading-away</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/fallingleaves.png"></p>

<p>Leaves sway down in sough late autumn winds, desolately, fading away, without one single sign.<!--more--></p>

<p>Fortunately trees' remaining vigor, notwithstanding in months' hibernation, new shoots would be pushing out after austere winters eventually.</p>

<p>Be hopeful and persistent, even through quite tough time, leastways&mdash;an opportunity to blossom.</p>

<p>&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Lives]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/03242014/about-lives/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-24T23:21:46+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/03242014/about-lives</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/mourning_angel.jpg"></p>

<p>The distance between life and death, might be far beyond the real boundary from life and death.<!--more--></p>

<p>It might need only one second separating fresh teary faces from pale freezing corpses. Or, seventeen days' passing eclipse infinite dread and heart-lacerating sorrow over these pathetic waiting families who have already withstood too much.</p>

<p>Time is a queer thing could not be explained reasonably which gives people shock, sadness, hope then and despair finally.</p>

<p>Since March 8th, no solid wreckages of MH370 are found yet. Maybe we would never find the aircraft. However, things become weird and bizarre thanks to kinds of press conferences, analyses, information from so-called concerned third parties. Emotions of the whole nation are affected like riding on the roller coasters, let alone the relatives.</p>

<p>The latest news, came unexpectedly without any warmth of humanity. A text message sending to relatives of the passengers onboard says that &ldquo;we have to assume beyond any reasonable doubt that MH370 has been lost and that none of those onboard survived.&rdquo; Maybe the planes was ended in the remote Southern Indian Ocean for it is &ldquo;far from any possible landing sites.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Cannot imagine those relatives' heartbreak.</p>

<p>Lives are so fragile that any good bye would become a farewell forever.</p>

<p>Please pray for the living, and mourn over the passing. Cherish every single moment sharing with your beloved. Treat life well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/03082014/about-time/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-08T19:31:58+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/03082014/about-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/Boeing777.jpg"></p>

<p><em>About Time</em> is a movie telling a young man could travel in time back to anytime in his own life changing what happens and what has happened.<!--more--></p>

<p>Well, if I am asked what could I change if I have such ability, what would I answer?</p>

<p>I have no idea.</p>

<p>Since the &ldquo;disappearance&rdquo; of the flight MH370, there would be more than 18 hours. Presume you would be a passenger on board, do you regret if it&rsquo;s the end of your life? Or suppose you&rsquo;re a relative/friend of someone on board, what do you think?</p>

<p>Useless anger in burst or refusal dinner with beloved?</p>

<p>So sorry that there would be no more chances for you. Actually, Lives are so fragile that &ldquo;Death could not be anticipated.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Just one moment, passing-aways are insulated from fresh lives. It&rsquo;s so quick beyond your response.</p>

<p>We are not the hero in that movie who could travel in time, we could be too helpless to change even a flash of time.</p>

<p>Please, living in the present, there would be even no opportunity for regretting.</p>

<p><strong>PS:</strong> Let&rsquo;s pray, for the best of those lost brothers and sisters.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[思維點滴_關於未來]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/02222014/si-wei-dian-di/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-22T21:36:20+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/02222014/si-wei-dian-di</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今天上午，參加大連春季招聘會，未有合適崗位可應聘。午飯和下午與摯友聚會，暢談關於現狀，關於未來。</p>

<p>將所聊的脈絡、思維點滴記錄如下：</p>

<ol>
<li><p>即將而立之年，可轉行，前提是所轉行業、方向對於自己有持續性(持久性)，需以事業(開拓)而非工作(餬口)之心面對；若非如此，需以已有經驗爲依託繼續深入，不可浮躁變換目標。</p></li>
<li><p>尋求可持續發展之道，至少使得自己(家人)的生活水平維持現狀(單身時期)。考慮年工資水平與漲幅、物價水平與漲幅、未來因組建家庭等原因的消費支出以及其他各方面因素，所選職業方向是否能夠完成上述目標。<!--more--></p></li>
<li><p>尋求揚長避短的發展軌跡，考慮自身的絕對優勢與相對優勢(參考<a href="http://wiki.mbalib.com/zh-tw/%E7%BB%9D%E5%AF%B9%E4%BC%98%E5%8A%BF%E7%90%86%E8%AE%BA">絕對優勢理論</a>)，選擇最適合自己的職業方向。</p></li>
<li><p>針對現狀，或者投資有較高回報率和持續性的項目，或者投資自身——MBA、研究生或其他，努力擴大自己的視野、思考高度和人際關係高度。</p></li>
<li><p>原始積累的獲取最為困難，如何借助外力，彼此協助，取得進展。</p></li>
<li><p>創業優先，就業其次。</p></li>
<li><p>不可急躁，不可輕易放棄；機遇若來，努力抓住；機遇未來，盡心準備。</p></li>
<li><p>最為可貴，在於知道自己想要什麼，正在做什麼，怎麼改變，怎麼改善。</p></li>
<li><p>正業副業並不矛盾，相互轉化，關鍵在於戰略性思考。</p></li>
<li><p>小心計劃，大膽嘗試，決斷方向，解決細節，不懼失敗，步步為營。</p></li>
<li><p>多看書，獨立、主動、批判性思考。</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
