<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: mood | Themis_Sword's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/categories/mood/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-10T22:34:55+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Themis_Sword]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[licong0419@outlook.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Am a Nerd/Weirdo/Crackpot.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04272015/i-am-a-nerd-slash-weirdo-slash-crackpot/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-27T19:50:26+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04272015/i-am-a-nerd-slash-weirdo-slash-crackpot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/rain.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Nerd</strong><br/>
: a person who behaves awkwardly around other people and usually has unstylish clothes, hair, etc.<br/>
: a person who is very interested in technical subjects, computers, etc.</p>

<p><strong>Weirdo</strong><br/>
: a strange or unusual person</p>

<p><strong>Crackpot</strong><br/>
: a person who is crazy or very strange</p>

<p>&mdash;From <strong><em><a href="http://www.merriam-webster.com">Merriam Webster Dictionary</a></em></strong></p>

<hr />

<!--more-->


<p>I have got no idea about the noun which could exactly describe myself&mdash;in Chinese I mean myself a 奇葩(QiPa).</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I am so languish not to lay down a backup flat sheet after the dirty one&rsquo;s been washed. However, I volunteered to have shower everyday as soon as getting back to my apartment.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I need washing my hair every morning. However, I could tolerant some tiny dirty spots on my pants or shoes and my those so-casual shirts.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I am too alone to attend &ldquo;unnecessary&rdquo; social or other activities. However, I am kind of eager to be understood and admitted.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I am only interested in American Justice related TV series and enough aware of their fictionality. However, I am hooked in such ethereal Justice, human right and happy ends.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I read a lot including fictional, non-fictional, scientific, technical, even Philosophical and Chinese medical. However, I could not make myself a thing nor be unconventional.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I try to be abstemious about daily basic necessities. However, I am somewhat squandering money on travelling, books(now I have a kindle), civil aircraft models and have no schedule about buying a house(or somewhere to shelter) even at present.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I know it&rsquo;s meaningless to be too reasonable with woman so well. However, I keep indulging myself into a dead-end state with the loved in so many specific aspects.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I give top priority nothing but love. However, I am so likely to be messed up in those trifles.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I thought I am firm and resolute sufficiently. However, I am thirsting for support and encouragement from the intimates.</p>

<p>I am a QiPa cuz I feel I understand, however, I don&rsquo;t.</p>

<p>Maybe, I am who I am, who is actually, non-existent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[About Love]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04212015/about-love/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-21T15:40:14+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04212015/about-love</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/love.jpg"></p>

<p><em>Whenever I get gloomy with the state of the world, I think about the arrival&rsquo;s gate at Heathrow airport. General opinion start to make out that we live in a world of hatred and greed. But I don&rsquo;t see that, seems to me that love is everywhere. Often it&rsquo;s not particularly dignified or newsworthy, but it&rsquo;s always there, fathers and sons, mothers and daughters, husbands and wives, boyfriend, girlfriend, old friends. When the plane hit the Twin Tower, as far as I know, none of the phone calls from people on board were messages of hate or revenge. They are all messages of love. If you look for it, I&rsquo;ve got a sneaky feeling that love actually is all around.</em>   <br/>
<strong>&mdash;&ldquo;Love Actually&rdquo; (Movie, 2003')</strong></p>

<!--more-->


<p><em>I have to tell you this and you need to hear it. I&rsquo;ve loved you since I met you&hellip; But I wouldn&rsquo;t allow myself to truly feel it until today. I was always thinking ahead. Making decisions out of fear. Today, because of what I learned from you&hellip; every choice I made was different and my life has completely changed. And I&rsquo;ve learned that if you do that, you&rsquo;re living your life fully. It doesn&rsquo;t matter if you have five minutes or fifty years. Samantha, if not for today, if not for you&hellip; I would never have known love at all. So thank you for being the person who taught me to love, and to be loved.</em>      <br/>
<strong>&mdash;&ldquo;If Only&rdquo; (Movie, 2004')</strong></p>

<p><em>The fountains mingle with the river
And the rivers with the Ocean,
The winds of Heaven mix for ever
With a sweet emotion;
Nothing in the world is single;
All things by a law divine
In one spirit meet and mingle,
Why not I with thine?</em></p>

<p><em>See the mountains kiss high Heaven
And the waves clasp one another;
No sister-flower would be forgiven
If it disdained its brother;
And the sunlight clasps the earth
And the moonbeams kiss the sea;
What is all this sweet work worth
If thou kiss not me?</em><br/>
<strong>&mdash;&ldquo;Love&rsquo;s Philosophy&rdquo; (Percy Bysshe Shelley, 1820')</strong></p>

<p><em>Let me not to the marriage of true minds
Admit impediments. Love is not love
Which alters when it alteration finds,
Or bends with the remover to remove:
O no; it is an ever-fixed mark,
That looks on tempests, and is never shaken;
It is the star to every wandering bark,
Whose worth&rsquo;s unknown, although his height be taken.
Love&rsquo;s not Time&rsquo;s fool, though rosy lips and cheeks
Within his bending sickle&rsquo;s compass come;
Love alters not with his brief hours and weeks,
But bears it out even to the edge of doom.
If this be error and upon me proved,
I never writ, nor no man ever loved.</em> <br/>
<strong>&mdash;&ldquo;Sonnet 116&rdquo; (Shakespeare, 1609')</strong></p>

<p>Love is not a word, it is a state of mind<br/>
Love is beyond a promise, it is a belief<br/>
Love is hope, it is also fortitude<br/>
Love makes a little green, but not so jealous<br/>
Love leads to a colorful dream, which is worth weaving and cherishing<br/>
Love means tolerating, which permits you being real<br/>
Love paints your life, furthermore harbors your soul.<br/>
Love is so hard to achieve, but it trully lasts.<br/>
<strong>&mdash;&ldquo;About Love&rdquo; (Themis_Sword, 2015')</strong></p>

<p><strong>I Love Thee! <a href="http://www.weibo.com/leah0204">@leah0204</a></strong></p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1moWxHdTkT0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Eve of Another Birthday]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04182015/the-eve-of-another-birthday/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-18T13:48:27+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04182015/the-eve-of-another-birthday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/life.jpg"></p>

<p>I almost forgot how old I am this year.</p>

<p>Thanks my parents for their affectionate SMS this morning wishing me a happy birthday and take-care overseas alone.</p>

<p>Actually, I might be solitary in a way rather than lonely.<!--more--></p>

<p>Retrospecting, It seems like I even don&rsquo;t tolerate continuing the &ldquo;insipid and mundane&rdquo; life traces no matter in which city of China. The gap between the so-called &ldquo;dream&rdquo; and reality keeps on tearing. I am kind of negative for picking that apple always higher despite my leaping and attempting. So I chose to leave(flounder) and chase a new style sitting in a classroom as a postgraduate student, overseas. There would be other choices for sure, nevertheless, I also need some fresh air.</p>

<p>Adaptability would never be an issue for me in the last ten years since my admission to university away from hometown without regarding to geographical position nor language speaking. So I live well for now, or, in other words, I survive well, for not self-sufficient.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m trying to stay hungary and foolish, so I study and review knowledge almost everyday without any passion of social networkings nor outdoor activities. Meanwhile, the efficiency of learning is not so satisfactory, frankly. The more materials or resources I consult, the more self-ignorant I feel, which is so frustrated. I could recall a professor&rsquo;s words <strong>&ldquo;Time Is the Only Enemy!&rdquo;</strong> on the registration day.</p>

<p>It doesn&rsquo;t mean living in a vacuum while no comparing with others' gains. Especially I&rsquo;m nothing but a student on the margin of my twenties. I remind myself that actually I am gaining much, in mental.</p>

<p>Thankfully, our transnational love evolves smoothly. As my motivity to move on so fearlessly, she is fabulous. Feeling comforting and cozy with her so much. Weaving our dreams and moreover, we are struggling, inch by inch, towards the brilliant future of ours.</p>

<p>It would be only quite an ordinary day of tomorrow, as for me, I&rsquo;d rather consider it another stair up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[...]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/12012014/dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T16:37:15+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/12012014/dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/adventure.jpg"></p>

<p>今天，2014年最後一個月的第一天，是該收拾下情緒了。</p>

<p>2014年，普通的不能再普通的一年，卻夾雜了太多的變化，這些變化，甚至改變了未來的方向。<!--more--></p>

<p>去年的辭職空檔期甚至延續到了今年的前五個月，超過整整七個月的空檔期，要算焦灼，還是焦慮，此刻的自己都回憶不起來那時，到底是什麼樣的心境。</p>

<p>還好，工作只是糊口的家什，事業才是值得追求和爭取的。</p>

<p>於是，工作，辭職，又工作。</p>

<p>直到現在，依然還算是沒有脫離“工作”的羈絆吧。</p>

<p>苦盡甘來？或許之前也不算苦，即使大半年像個游魂。</p>

<p>結識了True Friends，也遇到了她。</p>

<p>更安心了，就像久枯之地突然流過潺潺溪水；就靜靜的，靜靜的，直到心裏。如果硬要說有什麼不安，可能，是擔心自己不夠出色，不夠優秀，讓她委屈。</p>

<p>也收到了大學的offer，即將在新年啟程，去另一個國家，開始求學之旅，開始另一種人生。</p>

<p>自己很幸運，很幸運，不然，不會同時擁有，擁有一個愛人，擁有一份美好的未來。</p>

<p>此刻，耳機裏正好傳來最喜歡的那首“Forever in Love”。</p>

<p>感恩節剛過，如果說把“感恩”說出來，一遍兩遍三遍，未免太矯情。如此，心裏知道，便好。不求其他的，只求無愧、無悔。</p>

<p>還好，掙扎了這麼多年，還沒放棄。</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pieces]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/08302014/pieces/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-30T22:15:03+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/08302014/pieces</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/owlcoffee.jpg"></p>

<p>A friend said I am a traditional person intrinsically somehow with an attempt to break the invisible shackles, the boundary of the traditional and the nontraditional. I know it&rsquo;s true for I am raised and influenced since my juvenile in such family and society.<!--more--></p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s define the word &ldquo;traditional&rdquo; with the meaning of life styles with or close to Eastern world, and the word &ldquo;nontraditional&rdquo; with the opposite one.</p>

<p>With thousands years' culture of the doctrine of the mean in Eastern world, it would be so easy about choosing just like an objective question, following the tide and keeping away from too leftward or too rightward. It is also believed safe and reliable. If I am always as pure as a plain paper about my mind, there would be never so troublesome.</p>

<p>If comparing the modes of thinking as a curve of Normal Distribution, the curve in the Eastern world is supposed to be steep and thin while the curve in the Western world is supposed to be flat and fat, that is the difference. Persons' innate thoughts and exterior activities in the two environments are pulled or pushed from the two types of curve.</p>

<p>No readings, no worries. Especially when reading so many books about different life styles, thoughts, viewpoints and experiences of this flat world, notions' sparking and colliding in the consciousness. While endeavoring to experience colorful diversities of life, the farther you deviate, the stronger viscous forces pull you back to the curve. (Based on the theory of evolution, it would take tens or hundreds of generations to have a thorough change, of that curve, for the whole society.) And I also believe, it&rsquo;s true.</p>

<p>Retrospecting myself, what I would like to do is exploring this magnificent earth by reading thousands of books and traveling thousands of miles. Only after that, I could have a proper state of mind to choose and settle down. I would like to live a fresh and unique myself without considering what the general trends' choices. Obviously that&rsquo;s the reason  I am who I am. I would try to make some tiny changes within an invisible scope, the so-called margin of safety. As for others, I would be not so sure. Maybe that, the flounder, is some proof of my youth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
