<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: inspiring | Themis_Sword's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/categories/inspiring/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-14T21:32:14+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Themis_Sword]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[licong0419@outlook.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 20 Most Popular TED Talks of All Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04032015/the-20-most-popular-ted-talks-of-all-time/"/>
    <updated>2015-04-03T20:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.aprilzephyr.com/blog/04032015/the-20-most-popular-ted-talks-of-all-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/think.jpg"></p>

<p>Nonprofit organization TED launched in 1984 with a mission to present ideas worth sharing.</p>

<p>It has since become a cultural phenomenon, bringing together thought leaders from around the globe to give short, a few minutes talks about ideas that could change the world.</p>

<p>Of the more than 1,800 TED Talks, which have been viewed a total of 2.5 billion times across all platforms, a few have risen to the top. The following 20 talks are the most popular ever on Ted.com.<!--more--></p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/ken_robinson_says_schools_kill_creativity.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>
Sir Ken Robinson makes an entertaining and profoundly moving case for creating an education system that nurtures (rather than undermines) creativity.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/amy_cuddy_your_body_language_shapes_who_you_are.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Body language affects how others see us, but it may also change how we see ourselves. Social psychologist Amy Cuddy shows how “power posing” — standing in a posture of confidence, even when we don’t feel confident — can affect testosterone and cortisol levels in the brain, and might even have an impact on our chances for success.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/simon_sinek_how_great_leaders_inspire_action.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Simon Sinek has a simple but powerful model for inspirational leadership all starting with a golden circle and the question &ldquo;Why?&rdquo; His examples include Apple, Martin Luther King, and the Wright brothers &hellip; (Filmed at TEDxPugetSound.)</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/brene_brown_on_vulnerability.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Brené Brown studies human connection — our ability to empathize, belong, love. In a poignant, funny talk, she shares a deep insight from her research, one that sent her on a personal quest to know herself as well as to understand humanity. A talk to share.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/jill_bolte_taylor_s_powerful_stroke_of_insight.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Jill Bolte Taylor got a research opportunity few brain scientists would wish for: She had a massive stroke, and watched as her brain functions — motion, speech, self-awareness — shut down one by one. An astonishing story.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/pranav_mistry_the_thrilling_potential_of_sixthsense_technology.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>At TEDIndia, Pranav Mistry demos several tools that help the physical world interact with the world of data — including a deep look at his SixthSense device and a new, paradigm-shifting paper &ldquo;laptop.&rdquo; In an onstage Q&amp;A, Mistry says he&rsquo;ll open-source the software behind SixthSense, to open its possibilities to all.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/mary_roach_10_things_you_didn_t_know_about_orgasm.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>&ldquo;Bonk&rdquo; author Mary Roach delves into obscure scientific research, some of it centuries old, to make 10 surprising claims about sexual climax, ranging from the bizarre to the hilarious. (This talk is aimed at adults. Viewer discretion advised.)</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/tony_robbins_asks_why_we_do_what_we_do.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Tony Robbins discusses the &ldquo;invisible forces&rdquo; that motivate everyone&rsquo;s actions — and high-fives Al Gore in the front row.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/dan_pink_on_motivation.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Career analyst Dan Pink examines the puzzle of motivation, starting with a fact that social scientists know but most managers don&rsquo;t: Traditional rewards aren&rsquo;t always as effective as we think. Listen for illuminating stories — and maybe, a way forward.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/david_gallo_shows_underwater_astonishments.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>David Gallo shows jaw-dropping footage of amazing sea creatures, including a color-shifting cuttlefish, a perfectly camouflaged octopus, and a Times Square&rsquo;s worth of neon light displays from fish who live in the blackest depths of the ocean. This short talk celebrates the pioneering work of ocean explorers like Edith Widder and Roger Hanlon.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/dan_gilbert_asks_why_are_we_happy.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Dan Gilbert, author of &ldquo;Stumbling on Happiness,&rdquo; challenges the idea that we’ll be miserable if we don’t get what we want. Our &ldquo;psychological immune system&rdquo; lets us feel truly happy even when things don’t go as planned.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/susan_cain_the_power_of_introverts.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>In a culture where being social and outgoing are prized above all else, it can be difficult, even shameful, to be an introvert. But, as Susan Cain argues in this passionate talk, introverts bring extraordinary talents and abilities to the world, and should be encouraged and celebrated.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/pattie_maes_demos_the_sixth_sense.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>This demo — from Pattie Maes' lab at MIT, spearheaded by Pranav Mistry — was the buzz of TED. It&rsquo;s a wearable device with a projector that paves the way for profound interaction with our environment. Imagine &ldquo;Minority Report&rdquo; and then some.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/elizabeth_gilbert_on_genius.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Elizabeth Gilbert muses on the impossible things we expect from artists and geniuses — and shares the radical idea that, instead of the rare person &ldquo;being&rdquo; a genius, all of us &ldquo;have&rdquo; a genius. It&rsquo;s a funny, personal and surprisingly moving talk.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/hans_rosling_shows_the_best_stats_you_ve_ever_seen.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>You&rsquo;ve never seen data presented like this. With the drama and urgency of a sportscaster, statistics guru Hans Rosling debunks myths about the so-called &ldquo;developing world.&rdquo;</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/pamela_meyer_how_to_spot_a_liar.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>On any given day we&rsquo;re lied to from 10 to 200 times, and the clues to detect those lie can be subtle and counter-intuitive. Pamela Meyer, author of Liespotting, shows the manners and &ldquo;hotspots&rdquo; used by those trained to recognize deception — and she argues honesty is a value worth preserving.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/shawn_achor_the_happy_secret_to_better_work.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>We believe that we should work to be happy, but could that be backwards? In this fast-moving and entertaining talk, psychologist Shawn Achor argues that actually happiness inspires productivity. (Filmed at TEDxBloomington.)</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/david_blaine_how_i_held_my_breath_for_17_min.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>In this highly personal talk from TEDMED, magician and stuntman David Blaine describes what it took to hold his breath underwater for 17 minutes — a world record (only two minutes shorter than this entire talk!) — and what his often death-defying work means to him. Warning: do NOT try this at home.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/keith_barry_does_brain_magic.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>First, Keith Barry shows us how our brains can fool our bodies — in a trick that works via podcast too. Then he involves the audience in some jaw-dropping (and even a bit dangerous) feats of brain magic.</p>

<iframe src="https://embed-ssl.ted.com/talks/lang/en/cameron_russell_looks_aren_t_everything_believe_me_i_m_a_model.html" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>


<p>Cameron Russell admits she won “a genetic lottery”: she&rsquo;s tall, pretty and an underwear model. But don&rsquo;t judge her by her looks. In this fearless talk, she takes a wry look at the industry that had her looking highly seductive at barely 16 years old.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
